You can even win a reward!
I adjusted the transfer circle.
Now it will only facilitate travel between
here and the Clearflow Lake Stratum.
Oh, and don't worry,
monsters can't use it.
I made sure. Yay!
Good work, Hulemy!
Yes, well done.
Oh, working hard, huh?
Gotta say, I am impressed.
Once things settle down a bit, we should
head to the Clearflow Lake Stratum.
Hey, we're done with our patrol duty.
I didn't see any remnants in the village.
Man, I'm tired.
Captain, wanna tell me why I got
paired with the pervert? Who? Where?
Is someone using illusion magic, perhaps?
Where is the pervert of whom you speak?
Each of us has to take
their turn standing watch.
That's just the way it worked out.
Oh, I take no issue with it.
After all, is it not a gentleman's
duty to protect a small, frail lady?
Hey, Shui, relax!
Don't tell me to relax!
He kept digging old shoes
out of the collapsed houses,
and I had to watch his nose twitch
while he tried to smell them.
It's disgusting!
How sad.
I did not know she was emotionally
unstable, the poor dear.
Snip this! Get at it!
Well, this is some high-level combat.
Too bad it's between comrades, though.
Hey, Boxxo, you got a
moment to talk? Yeah.
I appreciate it.
Do you think you could stop by the Menagerie
of Fool's base once you're done here?
Eh? Here?
Yeah, in the origin stratum, conveniently.
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box,
but inside, I've still got a human soul.
In this new world of wonders,
I travel to and fro on the back
of my super-strong partner,
Lamas.
The name's Boxo. Hello there.
That means yes, by the way.
Interesting.
I didn't know the Menagerie had
their base in the Origins, Stratum.
Thanks for agreeing to talk, my friends.
We have something we need to tell
you, and it's long past overdue.
Yes, it is.
They deserve to know.
It'd be best.
Hold on.
Did I just see a shadow
cross Vilmina's face?
The red and white twins' mood
seems to have shifted, too.
What is going on here?
Come on, that's enough
messing around, you two!
Just give me a few more minutes!
I almost sunk one right
through this jerk's eye!
This is odd.
Is someone using mental
manipulation magic?
Because I hear strange childish chatter.
Sorry.
Seems we'll have to wait for
these two fools to settle down.
But then you can all
follow us to our base.
Hello there!
This is all news to me.
I had no idea the Menagerie of Fools
base was in the Origin Stratum.
Yeah, we didn't want many people to know.
Hey, how long have you been a member
of the Menagerie of Fools, Shui?
Hasn't even been two years yet.
Wait, are you telling me that Heavy's
been a member longer than you have?
Yes, I am indeed her senior.
Though it is worth noting
that we do not operate under a
troublesome vertical hierarchy
here in the Menagerie of Fools.
If we did,
that would require me to treat Aka and
Shiro with the respect one shows a superior.
I'm confused.
Aren't the twins quite
a bit younger than you?
You are correct, Hulemy.
Nevertheless,
the founding members of the menagerie are
Captain Kerioyl, Vice-Captain Filmina,
and then Aka and Shiro as well.
Those four started it all. Oh really?
I didn't even know that
and I'm a member too.
It's the first time Shui's heard this too?
Now that you mention it, those four
all disappear at once pretty often,
and they seem to work together a lot.
If you're curious, you should
ask them about it later.
What?
Oh, forgive my inattention, Master Boxo.
Hearing all that reminded me,
there's something I've been wondering
about for quite a while now.
Yes!
It's a sense I have about
Aka and Shiro's presence.
No, never mind.
I shouldn't go around
speculating about such things.
Well, now that you said something,
I am going to fixate on that.
What is...
Here you have it, the Menagerie's base.
Well, there's plenty of
ventilation, I'll give you that.
Oh, that's a decoy.
The real base is beyond this hidden door.
All right, come on down, everyone.
Hey, please, wherever you'd like, friends.
Boxo, would you mind dispensing
some refreshments for everyone?
Hello there!
Welcome to the Menagerie of Fools hideout.
We've gathered you here
today for one reason.
We figured it's time to share
our objective with you all.
First, a quick review.
I'm sure you all remember
how you can have a single
wish granted if you're able
to master this dungeon,
right?
I shall grant thee one
wish of thy choosing!
But only if thou reachest
the lowest stratum?
And offerest thy proof
that thou hast subdued.
a formidable stratum lord, end quote.
So goes the legend.
Yeah, and there was once a team?
Who reached the bottom
stratum of a dungeon!
in a land to the southwest.
Word in the strata is that they
did get their wishes granted.
But that's apparently when the
dungeon ceased to exist. What?
That means...
Are you saying that if somebody
gets their wish granted,
the Clearflow Lake stratum
will just disappear?
That's what I'm getting at.
And what happens to all the people
inside a dungeon when it ceases to exist?
Well, as I understand, they
get forcefully ejected from it.
But don't worry,
I made good and sure that nobody would
be destroyed along with the dungeon.
Good.
So the residents won't
get caught up in it.
So yeah.
The Vice-Captain and I felt it was
time that we revealed our wish.
And we're sorry to have kept it a
secret from you for so damn long.
What?
There's actually been a
door there this whole time?
Follow me this way.
Huh?
What in the world is that?
Seriously, what's going on here?
While it is faint, I do
sense a presence here.
I assume this youth is not dead.
This boy...
So, Mina and I are his parents.
Did he say boy?
As the captain says, this boy is our son.
Well, I am thoroughly confused.
Hold on, why isn't anyone
having much of a reaction?
I would assume a revelation like
this would elicit shouts of surprise.
What?
You're telling us you two are married?
That's what I was waiting for, Lamas.
I could tell there was something
going on between them by the fighting,
but I had no clue they
were married with a kid.
Much less that their kid
was asleep inside a crystal.
It'd be much more unnatural
not to be surprised.
Sorry to keep it a secret.
It's been nearly 20 years
since we got married.
Yes, my love. That it has.
We might as well share that Aka
and Shiro are our sons, too.
What?
I'm surprised you never caught on.
Sorry for the secrets.
It makes sense.
Aka and Shiro's presence
always seemed similar
to the captains and vice-captains to me.
What, not surprised, Evie?
I've never seen you lose your
cool, and to be perfectly frank,
I was kind of looking forward to it.
I'm sorry to betray your
expectations, Captain,
but I've had a vague notion
of it for a while now.
Man, you really are a
cunning one, aren't you?
So I guess all this means that you two
are that boy's big brothers then, right?
Not quite.
He's actually the oldest.
Yep, matter of fact, we're triplets.
What?
That's not all.
Before we reveal our wishes to you all,
we should explain the situation
with our sleeping son here.
You and me, I bet you already
know what this crystal is.
Well, it seems like it's
some form of crystal coffin.
Correct.
As I expected.
I'm not following.
It's an old magic item, though
ancient might be an even better word.
When you're inside one, a
person becomes frozen in time,
with all their biological
processes halted.
He's in there for a reason.
He has a negative blessing.
A negative blessing?
As you know, blessings are superpowers.
They're bestowed upon
us by a benevolent god.
Lamas has the blessing of might,
and I guess Boxo has his barrier.
On the other hand, a negative
blessing is the opposite.
A worthless power bestowed
by a malevolent god.
Thanks to that, our son couldn't
even manage everyday life.
We couldn't bear to watch
him get worse by the day.
So we decided to let him
stay here, unconscious,
until we could find a way to help him.
So time has stood still for him, and he's
remained the same age all these years.
The other two triplets
didn't have any issues.
He alone ended up with
a negative blessing.
As for what that is...
The blessing of decay.
An utterly horrid blessing where
not only does anything he touch rot,
but his own body would
also gradually decay.
To make matters worse, he was born
with the blessing of hyper-recovery.
He feels the pain of his
body continuously decaying,
all while it regenerates
due to hyper-recovery.
That vicious cycle will
continue until the day he dies.
How'd he get the negative blessing?
Once, a long time ago, we all but
wiped out a certain team of hunters.
And to get revenge,
they used an ancient cursed item to saddle
our poor family with this wretched fate.
But unfortunately,
it took me longer than
I cared to admit to even
realize he'd been given the
horrible blessing of decay.
By the time I figured it out, he could
hardly even get around because of the pain.
Great parenting, huh?
After hearing all this, it's clear.
Even an idiot could
guess what their wish is.
In case it's not obvious, our wish is
to get rid of his negative blessing.
We're prepared to do
anything to make it happen.
This crystal coffin's likely to be
effective for another year to two at most.
Maybe even less.
We don't have much time.
Now, for what we wanted to discuss.
Would you defect with us
to the Netherlord's side?
Foxo!
Would you defect to the Netherlord's side?
But Captain, how could you?
He's the one who tried to
kill us, or did you forget?
I would happily sacrifice
every single one of your
lives if it meant my son
would no longer be in pain.
My family is the most important
thing in the world to me.
For the sake of argument, let's just
say that we did agree to defect.
How would we even go about it?
The commander who was on this stratum
seems to be willing to arrange it.
She was already planning on contacting us,
actually, under the Netherlord's orders.
You don't say.
The four of us want to conquer the
strata and have our wish granted.
The Netherlord wants us to
get through to the final
stratum so we can take full
control over the dungeon.
Our interests happen to coincide.
You really think he'll honor
his side of the bargain?
You know who he is.
Yes, I know full well who he is.
But be realistic.
How long would it take for us to defeat him
and get the dungeon back to what it was?
We don't have near enough
time to do this the slow way.
Even if we know we're walking into a trap,
it's the only hope we have to cling to!
So I'll ask again.
Aren't there any of you who'd be
willing to defect along with us?
We know the situation now, but our
answer to that question is obvious.
So much for negotiation.
Well, that's too bad. You're Ekpa.
Too bad.
Boxxo, you're the one
we wanted most of all.
Boxxo stays with me no matter what.
I won't hand him over to anyone.
Part of a clergyman's duty is to lead
allies from Fali back to a righteous path.
Perhaps a little tap from my weapons
will knock you all back to your senses.
Or kill us.
It's not like we're planning
to go around killing anyone.
All we're going to do is use the
Netherlord so we can conquer the dungeon.
He's likely thinking something
along those same lines.
And he'll throw you to the
wolves once he's done with you.
Now what?
Blamas doesn't have full control
over her blessing and might.
It's too dangerous for her to
fight them under those conditions.
I know.
Thanks for the save, Boxxo.
Wait a minute, is this supposed to be me?
There's gotta be a better option.
Sa-o-bi.
I'll have to think of a
more appropriate nickname.
I'm sad to say it looks like
there's no avoiding a fight.
All right, let's do this, boys.
Heard loud and clear, Pops.
Didn't know you excelled
in post-combat, too.
Good enough, but barely.
Hey, I'm here too.
That's terrifying.
One hit would be lethal.
Don't worry, Akka.
If you die, I'll take care of the ladies
you were planning to hook up with.
I didn't want to fight,
but you're forcing my hand.
I want to jump in too, but the room's
so small, I'd hit my own people.
I guess I'll just have to count on
Mishel and Heavy to do the heavy lifting.
No pun intended.
Don't tell me you're
slowing down already, Heavy.
I didn't expect your
blades to be poisoned.
Hey, now, the poison won't kill you.
It'll just make you
hurt real bad all over.
Hold on.
Why isn't it hurting you?
Oh, well, that would be
because I'm using my blessing.
It can temporarily relieve pain.
You have a blessing that can relieve pain?
Yes.
Neither the illusions nor
mind meddling are magic.
They're my blessing of
sensory manipulation.
I've never heard of a blessing like that.
Oh, Hulemy.
Methinks you might have
heard of my blessing.
Yeah.
As far as blessings go, it's
about as rare as Boxo's Barrier.
Are you cool with me explaining it?
Indeed.
I would not object there.
This very rare blessing allows
you to control a person's senses,
to manipulate their sight,
hearing, smell, and taste,?
and potentially control
the sensation of pain.
Wait a minute!
Are you saying it could
get rid of my son's pain?
Unfortunately, no.
I cannot use its analgesic
effect on other people.
We'll dagnab it.
I do apologize.
I hate to disappoint you.
Fighting against you is such a bummer!
Can't you, like, hold back even
just a little and let you get away?
I think not. Wilmena! Aka! Shiro! Yay!
Here we go! What's this?
Are they about to try something?
What's going on he was fine
just a moment ago heavy
i don't know what he did
to heavy But whatever they
try i'll repel it with my
barrier heavy's not the
only one in this Fight who's
been hiding what he can do
But i didn't turn it off
This is the same spell filmina used in
the battle against the crocodile fiends I
never thought I'd have to use the secret
weapon I was saving for the Nether Lord.
Master Botso! Comrades!
I will give chase immediately!
No, don't!
We don't know what the captain's power
does, so going after him is too risky.
We should see to Heavy first.
Alas, they really fooled us, eh?
I suppose the man's not
our captain for nothing.
How can you be so calm about this?
Were you putting on an
act to help them get away?
No, and perish the thought.
Severe pain had me waylaid
till mere moments ago.
Even right now, as we speak,
I am once again using my blessing
to relieve the waves of agony.
His blessing halted your blessing
and neutralized Boxo's barrier, too?
Also, the captain's eyes
were glowing red back there.
Yeah, that was creepy.
They were bright red.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
From that data, my guess is that
it's the blessing of eye breach.
It's practically a legend, but it
lets you negate other blessings.
The captain's blessing of eye
breach means serious trouble for me.
If I can't use my barrier or telekinesis,
I'm nothing but a
convenient vending machine.
Oh, right.
That's still a useful
thing to be, I guess.
We need to report this to
the director immediately.
Shall we return to the
village and seek him out?
Yeah, we had better do that.
They just ran off and didn't think
twice about leaving their son behind.
They must know we would
never harm the poor child.
He has done nothing wrong after all.
To get right to the point, I added Kerry
Oil and the others to the wanted list.
To think that our comrades would betray us,
it would appear I have been quite naive.
Sorry.
I wish they would have
told us about it from
the start before making this awful choice.
The Vice-Captain's temperament
probably had something to do with it.
She isn't good at asking for help.
I still wish they would
have just talked to us.
Yes, me too.
The way they left their
precious son behind,
that might be our fool captain's
way of sending a cryptic message.
If only they hadn't felt
backed into a corner.
I should probably feel angry that
they've done something so treacherous,
but I don't know.
I just can't bring myself to.
Yes, well, if we can
believe what Kerry Oil said,
they'll likely go to the final stratum and
begin their foolish attempt to conquer it.
One question.
How do you suppose they mean
to travel between strata?
I had that same thought.
The Netherlord might have some magic item
that allows for movement between strata.
Or they could be planning
to defeat the Stratum
Lords and use the transfer
circles from that.
Oh, right.
There's a Stratum Lord in
the depths of each stratum.
A transfer circle appears
when you defeat one.
At the same time,
I don't think we really need to worry that
they'll conquer the dungeon anytime soon.
What do you mean?
That the four of them are not
nearly powerful enough on their own.
If they truly mean to
outmaneuver the Netherlord,
they'll need to enlist
some trustworthy comrades.
Which means they'll likely try to win over
someone new or recruit old acquaintances.
Oh, the other two menagerie folks.
Ah, yes, talk about a pair of oddballs.
If the captain can manage
to cajole or bribe them,
I can very well see them
coming to his family's aid.
Uh, I wouldn't rule that out.
Damn, if Heavy's calling them oddballs,
then those two have got to be super weird.
With that in mind, I think
we should update our plan.
While we're attempting to restore
the peace on each stratum,
we should also attempt
to make contact with the
remaining members and win
them over to our side.
Excellent, Director.
However, while I know those two can
be found somewhere in the dungeon,
I have no notion of which
stratum they might be on.
It was once my duty to locate
them for the menagerie,
but that was before my
unfortunate imprisonment.
In the middle of an important mission,
he was detained for acts of perversion.
Back to more pressing matters.
We're in a bit of a bind now since we
can't travel freely between strata.
Then I think we should return
to the Clearflow Lake Stratum.
Restoration has only just begun.
There's a long list of things to do.
Yeah, he's right.
Time to head back to Clearflow
Lake Stratum, everyone.
So many intense things
happen on this stratum.
It's sure been a crazy time
to be a vending machine.
Here I am, doing something as important as
crushing the Netherlord's evil ambitions.
That would make sense if I were in
the role of some legendary hero,
but, like, I'm a vending machine.
Nevertheless, while my body might be
inorganic, my heart is still human.
I want to save everyone.
A lot has happened, but let's
fight on together, Boxo.
Hello there.
Well, I don't know how much I
can manage as a vending machine,
but I do know I'll devote all my electricity
to keeping Lamas and me together.
All right, I'm activating it now.
Has it been tampered with?
What's going on?
Everyone, evacuate the transfer circle.
Yeah, I would, except I can't even move.
Mokso! Mokso!
Huh?
Where am I?
This isn't good.
Did I get sent to some
other stratum by myself?
Based on what Hulemy was shouting,
something must have gone wrong
with the transfer circle.
I hope everyone's okay, and
I'm worried about llamas.
Oh, I'd better move, or I'll be in
the way if someone else transfers.
Okay, so now what?
Should I find a way to
open the door and go out?
Or wait here and see who comes?
Hulemy, Director Bear, Llamas, huh?
Where's Llamas?
I don't know what I'm saying to you,
but I don't know what
I'm saying to you.
I'm going to take a step and take a step.
I'm going to walk you through.
I'm going to take a step.
I'm going to change tomorrow!
This melody?
I'm going to go over the way.
I'm going to move on.
I'm going to be the only one.
See you
next time.
You could even win a reward.
I look forward to serving you again.